Alright! Welcome to the course. In this
section of the course, we're gonna start
laying down a baseline. What we need to
do is start establishing a common
terminology and some of the terminology
around SQL like what is a database? What
is a relational model? And things like
that. We have some lectures in this
section of the course. They are just
Powerpoints. They're going to talk about
the history of SQL and MySQL, about
the programming languages, some the key
concepts so we can get that base
terminology down and we're gonna get
some hands-on too. So I'm gonna keep it a
little bit fluid but we also need to
kind of start establishing a baseline of
some common terminology that we can use
going forward.
So I'm gonna try to make it too boring
because I know saying through
powerpoints can be pretty slow and
boring but hopefully you'll get a lot of
benefit and start a really understanding
why SQL is used? Where it came from?
How it came to be? And little bit of a
history of SQL in the industry.